Inventory of the Marek Rudzki collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Marek Rudzki collection
1944-1987
2008C54
Hoover Institution Archives
9 manuscript boxes (3.6 linear feet)
Serial issues, bulletins, and other printed matter, relating to civil liberties and political conditions in Poland. Includes underground dissident publications from Poland and supporting publications published in other countries.
Rudzki, Marek, 1930-, collector
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Serial issues, bulletins, and other printed matter, relating to civil liberties and political conditions in Poland. Includes underground dissident publications from Poland and supporting publications published in other countries.
Civil rights--Poland.; Poland--Politics and government--1980-1989.; Underground literature--Poland.
- Biographical file, Rudzki family (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
- Countries file (Box 1-8)
  - Australia, Czechoslovak émigrés (Box 1)
  - Belgium file (Box 1)
    - Solidarnosc, Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Report on repressions in Poland since December 13, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Canada, Slowo Solidarnosci, 1982 (Box 1)
  - France file (Box 1-3)
    - General (Box 1)
      - General (Box 1)
      - Clippings (Box 1)
    - Art Press, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Hebdomadaire Solidarnosc, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Kontakt, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
    - L'Alternative, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Solidarnosc Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
    - Solidarnosc Pol-Presse, Lettre Hebdomadaire d'Information sur la Pologne, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Germany file (Box 4)
    - General (Box 4)
    - Przekazy, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
    - Die Wende - Przemiany, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Great Britain file (Box 4)
    - General (Box 4)
      - General (Box 4)
      - Monographs (Box 4)
    - Dziennik Polski, 1980-1985 (Box 4)
    - Orzel Bialy, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
    - Puls, 1982-1984 (Box 4)
    - Robotnik, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Voice of Poland, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Italy, Christian publications, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Poland file (Box 5-7)
    - Government publications (Box 5)
      - Krajowa Agencja Informacyjna, 1985 (Box 5)
      - Poland Monthly, 1978, 1983 (Box 5)
      - Polityka, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
      - Zycie Literackie, 1981 (Box 5)
      - Zycie Warszawy, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Underground publications (Box 6-7)
      - General (Box 6)
        - General (Box 6)
        - Book announcements (Box 6)
        - Clippings (Box 6)
        - Flyers, postcards, posters (Box 6)
        - World War II: daily reports and flyers from Nalecz region at the time of German withdrawal and Soviet occupation of Poland, 1944 (Box 6)
      - 13 Grudnia, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
      - Komitet Obrony Robotnikow, 1977 (Box 6)
      - Komitet Oporu Spolecznego, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
      - Jaruzela, 1984 (Box 6)
      - Kultura Niezalezna, 1985 (Box 6)
      - Niepodleglosc, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
      - Polonia Resurecta, Inty Rozewicz (Box 7)
      - Solidarnosc 500 Pierwszych Dni, 1982 (Box 7)
      - Solidarnosc Walczaca, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
      - Tygodnik Solidarnosci, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Sweden file (Box 7)
    - Vaelkommen Till Sverige, 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Sprzeci, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - United States file (Box 8)
    - General (Box 8)
      - Clippings (Box 8)
    - AFL-CIO Free Trade Union News, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
    - Bulletin Solidarnosc, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
    - Committee in Support of Solidarity, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
    - Konfederacja Polski Niepodleglej, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
    - Pomost (Box 8-9)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 8)
      - 1983 (Box 8)
      - 1987 (Box 9)
    - Wycinanki: Wybor Artykulow z Polskiej Prasy Emigracyjnej, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - RFE-RL Radio Free Europe Research, 1981-1983 (Box 9)
- Subject file (Box 9)
  - Fallaci, Oriana, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Internment camps, 1982 (Box 9)
  - John Paul II and Christian movement, 1980s (Box 9)
  - Katyn (Box 9)
  - Russian language publications, 1978-1982? (Box 9)